- Previously on "Pretty Little Liars"...
- ...End up like me.
Do you know who's doing this? No, but I
also know that "A" isn't playing around.
We have three hours to find out
who "A" is before "A" finds us.
This is "A's" lair.
"A" is dressed
like the black swan.
I don't want Aria with him
any more than you do,
but if you back him into a corner,
nobody will end up happy.
You're connected to Jenna
and Ian and Jason...
almost like you guys were
members of the same club.
You're under arrest.
For what?
The murder of
Alison DiLaurentis.
It's about revenge.
You deserved
everything you got.
Mona's "A."
Mona!
They think it's over. Loser
Mona's going to the nuthouse,
and those precious liars
are going home to sleep
with their windows open
and their doors unlocked.
Don't they know
that's what we want?
They found a body.
They think it's Maya.
Em, you and I are the only ones
who did anything
worth talking about this summer.
Aria took some boring picture class
and Spencer went to college.
I took a full load at Hollis,
and Aria beat out
a thousands applicants
for a space in that
photography class.
So, how many houses
did you build?
Uh, I think
we finished about six.
And in poor countries,
one house is like
a home for fifty.
Okay, Miss Productive.
How much of your list
did you actually do?
Let's see...
Cooking class with Caleb.
Done.
Volunteer at the Animal
Shelter for pocket dogs...
Wait. That exists?
Did not do.
Expand my vocabulary.
"Effectuating."
Interned for Vera Wang. You got
an internship for Vera Wang?
Yeah, I changed my mind.
Turns out they want you
to work for free.
Was that a car?
Maybe for you, you're a pixie.
I've gotten
really good at this.
"Show me your boobs. 'A'."
Does Mona have a ten-year-old brother?
"A" for "annoying."
Are these ever gonna stop?
Eventually we'll be old news.
Yeah, and then Garrett will go on
trial and we'll be news again.
Or Mona will start talking
and we'll be news again.
Or I'll show someone my boobs
Okay!
Hey, I thought
this was a party.
You know what? You're right, Em.
Welcome back.
And you're never allowed to leave
for an entire summer again.
To making it to senior year.
Hear!
Not all of us made it.
I'm sorry, Em.
I didn't mean it like that.
To Maya.
Em, you know that
we're here for you.
To Maya. To Maya. To Maya.
Hanna.
Where's Emily and Spencer?
I don't know.
I need an aspirin
and a trough of water.
- Emily?
- She's gone.
What do you mean she's gone?
I've looked everywhere.
Pretty Little Liars - 3x01 - It Happened "That Night"
Original air date: 05.06.2012.
Sync & corrections by into-the-light,
www.addic7ed.com
How could she not
remember anything?
She's totally out of it.
She's still drunk.
You don't think that she had
anything to do with this, do you?
No! She...
she can hardly stand.
How did she get here?
Hann, hand me Em's phone.
Em, you got a blocked call
at eleven.
Who was it? Do you remember
who you talked to?
Um... I think I remember
leaving your house,
and the next thing I know you
guys are calling me and I'm here.
- What? That can't be right.
- What is it?
It says that at midnight
she got a call from my phone.
You were asleep, right?
Oh, my God. Somebody
called Emily from my phone.
Somebody was in my house.
You guys, this is a set-up.
What was that?
We need to get out of here.
Now.
Come on.
If I never see another shovel
again, it'll be too soon.
Wait. Do we wipe it off
or something?
Do we wipe off the prints?
Who would do this to Emily?
Who would do it to Ali?
Some twisted psycho.
The only twisted psycho we know
is locked up at Radley.
Let's get out of here.
Everything?
Everything.
The only person who benefits from
a missing body is Ali's killer.
He killed Maya, too.
I know, Em.
And Garrett's gonna
rot in hell for it.
Jenna wouldn't help Garrett.
She put him in jail.
What about your sister?
She's in Philadelphia,
and as far as we know,
the only thing she's guilty of is being
in Ali's room the night that she died.
There has to be someone else...
Someone we don't know
who's connected to Garrett.
Duck.
Really?
Get down!
It's Lucas. What is he
doing out so late?
Shh!
Hanna, he can't hear us.
What's going on?
We're leaving.
We're going to the lake house.
When my mom reads this note, she'll think that
we've been up there since this afternoon.
Em?
Hello?
I'm sorry if I woke you up.
I don't know how to
tell you this...
Were there... Any witnesses?
No, mom, I...
I understand.
Okay, bye.
The caretaker called it in
this morning.
The place is crawling
with reporters,
but the police
don't have any leads.
So we're okay.
Nobody saw us.
Yeah.
I'm so sorry, guys.
This is all my fault.
No one's blaming you.
Yeah, Em. Somebody
took you there
to make it look like
you dug up Ali's body.
And I made it so easy.
If I wasn't so wasted...
Em.
Last night never happened.
Are we sure about that?
We can still go to the cops.
We can tell them the truth.
We don't even know
what the truth is.
Okay.
We got up here
yesterday afternoon.
We roasted some marshmallows,
we talked about how much fun
senior year is gonna be, and...
We went to bed early.
Em?
I understand.
Last night never happened.
Ar... you okay?
Aria.
I thought
the nightmares stopped.
I guess they started again.
Hey...
You're still safe, Aria.
There's no more "A."
You were far away from
this mess last night.
Thank God you stayed
at Spencer's lake house.
Did you read this?
Apparently Maya found some
things that belonged to Alison.
No, no. She...
she gave everything to Jason.
Well, actually, they think
she may have kept something,
something that connected Garrett
to Alison's murder.
That doesn't make sense.
She would have told Emily.
Well, maybe that's what she was on her
way to do, but Garrett found her first.
Do you know what
this weekend is?
How could I forget?
Labor Day is the anniversary
of Alison's death.
Or...
I was about to start
a teaching job,
and you thought you
might like to teach...
Was that true, or were
you just hitting on me?
Did you really play B26, or
were you just hitting on me?
Can we make this... our
anniversary instead of hers?
Meet me tomorrow night
at the Rosewood Grille.
I will be the guy at the bar
reading Ulysses.
You still haven't
finished that book?
No one has.
I'm just a hopeless romantic.
I thought we could
recreate the date.
I wouldn't exactly
call it a date.
We ended the night
in the bathroom.
I remember.
I think it went
something like... This?
And then I did
something like this...
Hanna?
You like this?
Yeah, I love it...
For a pregnant woman.
Is there something
I need to know?
I'd need to have sex
to get pregnant.
Ew! Mom,
that's gross.
Well, since when did you
become a prude?
Since you intimated
that you want to have sex.
Hanna... all right,
you're allowed to date,
but you're not...
Open for business.
Hanna... are you starting
a business, Ashley?
Go. Shop.
I was hoping a little
retail therapy
might take Hanna's mind
off the headlines.
Yeah, one murder
makes the news,
but two dead girls
and a missing body?
How big is your closet?
He did it, right?
Garrett hired someone
to dig up that grave?
This hasn't made the papers,
but the prosecution had petitioned
to have the body exhumed,
but it was gone before
the judge could make his ruling.
I don't think
it's a coincidence.
Can I just tell you, I am so relieved that
the girls were out of town last night.
For once they were reading the
news instead of making it.
_
It was just Toby.
I'll call him back.
Does he like the loft?
Well, he comes over
to shower every day
because the plumbing is broken,
so I really like the loft.
We are always going to be
those girls who knew Alison.
And now Maya.
Hey! You know what? I could ta a
a picture and send it to you.
Look, I keep on replaying
last night in my head.
Hanna, there was
somebody in my house.
While we were sound asleep,
they were right there,
they were in
the same room as us.
Just as I was starting
to feel safe again.
I just... I really
want to turn my brain off.
- Can we ditch our moms and go catch a movie?
- Ohh, I can't.
I have an appointment
with Dr. Sullivan.
Oh. You're seeing her
again?
Yeah. A little.
But you...
Wouldn't tell her about...
No!
Come on, I wouldn't
do that to Emily.
Yeah, but it's not just Emily.
We were all there.
Hanna, we should get going.
Okay.
You know what,
I'll call you later.
Okay.
Oops.
Almost forgot.
You'll need to wear it
while you're on this floor.
We still haven't
seen any changes,
but I'm sure she appreciates
your visits.
Your friend is here.
Can you say hello?
That was a reporter
at the door.
Whoever took Ali's body gave him
reason to start knocking again.
What did you say to him?
Before I slammed the door
in his face, or after?
You know, you made
a difference this summer, Em.
And I think
Maya would have been proud.
I know I am.
It was a lot easier
to pound nails in Haiti
than it would have been
to stay here.
You know, when grandma died,
I thought I would carry
that grief with me forever.
But time really does help...
And eventually
it stops hurting so much.
I'm okay, mom.
Really.
Birds, birds, birds.
You cannot find a top this
season without feathers on it.
Are you gonna look
right through me forever?
Look, it's not easy
for me to get here, okay?
I have been lying to
everyone I care about for weeks,
and after what happened
last night, I...
I need you to understand
something.
I am not doing this for you.
I'm here for me.
I want to know what I did
to make you hate me so much.
Hanna?
Um, no.
No, you must have me
confused with someone else.
Oh, Miss Rivers, I'm sorry.
Your resemblance
to an old friend is uncanny.
Please don't tell
anybody that you saw me here.
What are doing here?
What are you doing here?
I volunteer a few days a month.
Quid pro quo. What?
It's your turn.
Look, she owes me some answers.
I need it to make sense.
Sense is something rarely mined
from mental illness.
Trust me, I've spent
a lifetime trying.
I'm starting
to figure that out.
I mean, I don't think
I can keep coming back.
It's like she doesn't
even know that I'm here.
Come here.
I promise I'll get the plumbing fixed
in the loft by the end of the week.
Oh, no, it's no rush at all.
Really. There's...
There's no rush.
Are your parents still out?
Yes...
You know that's my shirt.
And you're never
getting it back.
I don't want it back.
You look better in it
than I do.
Mmm.
Okay, I know that
it was my idea to wait...
But right now I'm just
completely forgetting why.
You'll remember
after I put some clothes on.
I am so happy you guys
decided to go to
the lake house yesterday.
Yeah, me too.
I can't imagine what went through
your head when your mom called you.
Can we not talk about it?
Just the thought of somebody
doing that to Alison is really...
Of course.
Mmm.
I'll call you later.
Yes, please.
So let's meet up after
and go to the store together.
I can't. I have an appointment
with Dr. Sullivan.
Can you do it? I though the point of
cooking together was being together.
It is. And I promise, when I get back
we will make an unforgettable dong po.
Say it again.
No!
Please!
No.
Do you want me
to go to the store?
Dong po.
Gimme the list.
Even if I say his name we get sucked
into this vortex of awkwardness.
And my dad pretends
like he can't hear,
but his neck gets all red and then his
face pinches up like he's constipated.
So basically Ezra
is like Lord Voldemort.
Hey.
Hi, Lucas.
He knows something.
I thought you said he didn't
see you guys. He didn't.
It's no coincidence that he turned
dark after the masquerade ball.
Jenna has that effect
on people.
Yeah, but she's been gone all
summer, and he's still Boo Radley.
Have you ever noticed how many
skinny brunettes go to this school?
She fits the costume.
Has anybody heard from Emily?
No. I left her
a bunch of messages.
Yeah, me too.
Hope she's okay.
Hello?
Help!
Somebody help me!
Aria.
Aria, are you ok?
I had a panic attack.
Guys, I think I saw "A."
No, you didn't, ok?
Mona is in a straight jacket at Radley.
Yeah, I-I heard that's she's
practicaly in a coma over there.
Or that girl interrupted thing could
just be an act to keep her out of jail.
I mean, you know what she's
capable of... we all do.
Yeah, but she can't
hurt us anymore, okay?
Bitch crazy.
Don't worry, Aria. Someday
we will all have jubilation.
That was a really good
use of that word, Hann.
Are you sure
you don't want to come?
Yeah, I just have
one last test to study for.
Oh, it's a long weekend, honey.
You can put in hours tomorrow.
I know...
I really could use
the extra day.
Come on, a girls night out
in the city might be fun.
Like old times.
Before your sister...
Mom, Melissa is a Hastings.
We bounce back like superballs.
Don't work too hard.
Okay.
Bye.
Have fun.
Aw, you gave this to me
for Mother's Day.
This poor girl just can't
get any peace.
Mom, I love you, but can we please
just not talk about Alison?
I need a break from that.
You know, I wouldn't
take any of it back,
and neither would your father.
Are you sure
this is what you want?
When your father and I met,
we were so young.
But as life got
more complicated...
It was just harder for us
to find ways to compromise.
You're talking about me and Ezra.
We're the complication.
No. That is just one of the many
issues we couldn't agree on.
Yeah, but it's... it's the one
that drove you two apart.
That is absolutely not true.
We're just too different now.
And that's okay. I don't want to
pretend to be somebody that I'm not,
and your father
shouldn't have to either.
Remember when I was thirteen
and you took me
to that grown-up lunch
and you... You made me a
promise to allow me to be me.
Of course.
Mom, you're doing that.
By not shutting out Ezra, you're
allowing me to be who I want to be.
Well, I haven't exactly
welcomed him with open arms.
No. But you don't cringe
when I say his name.
Or look constipated
like your father does.
- You noticed that too?
- Yeah.
Hey.
You look great, Em.
You really do.
You look happy.
I am.
I'm sorry if I took you
away from Spencer.
It's a holiday weekend,
I'm sure you guys had plans.
It's okay. She's got
one last test, so...
- She's studying.
- Yeah.
Thanks, Angie.
So, when did you move upstairs?
I started the remodel
a few weeks ago.
I mean, it's still roughing it,
but I get to live for free
while I do the work.
And it feels really good
to be out on my own.
How's Jenna?
I haven't talked to her
since she left town.
Are you okay, Emily?
I don't...
I don't think I am.
It's all over the news.
What kind of a sick person
would do something like that?
There's something
I need to talk to you about.
How was the shrink?
It was fine.
What do you guys talk about?
Stuff.
Do you talk about us?
No.
How can you not talk about us?
We're intimate.
We're what?
Yeah, let's just forget that.
You just said the "I" word.
You should get that.
I have never heard a guy
say the "I" word.
Here.
Well, you're saved.
It's Spencer.
We have to talk about
this pool thing for tomorrow.
Hello?
Is Miss Rivers available?
How'd you get my number?
I took a chance that Miss Rivers'
emergency contact Harvey Marin
might, in fact, be Hanna Marin.
Is something wrong with Mona?
Other than the obvious?
Is that brit humor?
Because it's not funny.
I'm sorry, I have
a very dry sense of humor.
Can you just cut to the chase?
Mona's making progress,
and her doctor thinks that
your visits may be helping.
What kind of progress?
You should come by tomorrow
and see for yourself.
Hey.
Everything okay?
Spencer, I don't want to eat raw veggies
if we're hanging out in bikinis all day.
But chips and salsa
sounds great!
Uh, pardon?
Bye, Spencer.
Good night.
I spent half the summer
partying way too much.
I've just been so angry.
Em, that's understandable.
I can't imagine
losing someone that way.
I was at this one party
and I got so wasted
I don't even
remember being there.
You don't remember anything?
I really let my friends down.
You know how Spencer and
the girls feel about you.
Yeah, but they're like my family.
That's why I can't stand
to disappoint them.
That's what's so great about
friends... they're not your family.
They accept you
for who you are.
I'm listening.
Aria, the police are here.
They want to talk to you.
We went to Spencer's lake house.
We made a fire and Emily showed
us pictures from the trip.
We spent the evening
catching up.
It was a pretty low-key night.
I'll call you
when we get home. Okay.
Are they charging them?
No, it's just routine.
The girls were at
your lake house last night.
I don't understand
why they're being questioned.
They said it was part of
the ongoing investigation.
And you believe that?
Uh, excuse me.
Have you seen her?
Is she okay?
She hasn't come out yet.
Look, I get why you're here,
and I'm sure
she'd appreciate it,
but I think the last thing
she needs right now
is the police questioning her
relationship with a former teacher.
I thought we were past this.
Are you okay?
Do I need to talk to them?
No, I'm fine. I just
want to get out of here.
We could still make
our reservation.
Or maybe we could
do this another time?
I'm sure we could all
use a bite, right?
Yes. Um, let's go.
They've had you on
a lot of medication,
so I don't know
if you remember,
but I've been visiting you
for a couple of weeks now.
Remember that cute doctor
from Rosewood Memorial?
The one who was engaged
to Spencer's sister?
Of course you do.
You're "A."
Well, he thinks my visits
have been helping you...
So if you want,
I can keep coming back.
Is it something you want?
Could have been you
behind this glass.
The cops were so close
to pinning it on you.
I'm sorry I had to
keep calling you like that.
I know what you think of me...
But I swear to you,
I didn't do it.
All of the evidence they
have against me, it's bogus.
You said that
you would tell me the truth.
So what is it?
There's a lot
you don't know, Spencer.
Some of it
you don't want to know.
Do you think there's any chance I'm
gonna get a fair trial in this town?
Everybody already thinks
I'm guilty.
I don't know anything
about Maya,
but I may know
who killed Alison.
I'm listening.
I need a lawyer, and your mom's
one of the best in the state.
No. I'm not going to help you.
You're not safe, Spencer,
and your friends aren't either.
You're just trying to scare me.
It's not over!
Do you hear me?
I know who took the body!
_
I'll try one more time.
Why wasn't she
at the police station?
Do you think
she told 'em the truth?
If she told 'em the truth,
we wouldn't be standing here.
Em, that was me calling you.
Where have you been?
It's okay. If you told them the
truth, we'll figure something out.
No, I would never
do that to you guys.
They called all three of us
into the station.
Where were you?
We were so worried.
I didn't have my phone
with me yesterday.
And when I got home last night,
the cops were waiting for me.
But I told them everything
that we agreed on. Everything.
Then why are you so upset?
Because if it wasn't for me,
we wouldn't be at the wrong
place at the wrong time,
and it could haunt us forever.
Em, it's fine. Okay?
We've dealt with it.
I saw you guys
at school yesterday,
and all I could think about
was because of me...
Because of you, nothing.
Okay? Nobody saw us,
and if we just stick to our
story, we are in the clear.
I remembered something...
About that night.
That's it?
That's all you remember?
I found out online
that some people forget things
because they don't want
to remember.
And if this is selective,
then anything can trigger it...
sights, smells, sounds.
So the car that you saw,
it just looked like the car from
that night, or it was the car?
I don't know.
I started to talk towards it
because I wanted to look inside,
but... I got a text.
And the person that sent it to me
knows I don't remember what happened.
"I bet you remember me."
Guys, is it starting again?
No. You guys,
that's not "A."
Mona is "A," and she's drooling
in her bed at a nut hospital.
We don't know that for sure.
Yeah, we do.
I've been visiting her.
What?
I didn't tell you because
I knew you'd think I'm crazy.
Yeah.
She tried to kill you, Hanna.
She's locked up in a room
with bars over her windows.
Trust me, she doesn't know
anything that happened that night.
Yeah, well, someone does.
There's something
I need to show you guys.
Ali's shrine
is right over there...
And then over here she had a row of black
hoodies all just perfectly hanging,
- ready for "A" to grab one and run.
- Mona.
Ready for Mona.
Yeah.
And there was a zombie costume
hanging on the back of that door.
Just like the one that
attacked Ali on Halloween.
O-okay, so you've been
coming here all summer
trying to remember
what was in this room. Why?
We have to
tell Emily the truth.
The morning after they found
Mona's body, we came back here.
Yeah, to get rid of everything.
I know. You told me.
We lied to you.
We didn't want it to be another
thing you had to worry about.
When we came back here,
it was empty.
The file cabinets,
the maps, pictures,
Ali's diaries...
everything was gone.
Maybe the police took it.
If the police found out what Mona knows
about us, my mom would be in jail.
Yeah, Ezra too.
So who took it?
There are things that
don't really add up.
Like Mona was with you when
"A" gave Emily that massage.
And there's no way that she
could have gotten Ian's body
out of the bell tower
by herself.
Wait. You're saying that you
think someone was helping her?
If the black swan
wasn't guilty of something,
why would she
run from you guys?
"Mona played with dolls.
I play with body parts."
"Game on, bitches."
"A."
Sync & corrections by into-the-light,
www.addic7ed.com